Okay, I want to show you another way to
um change an attribute and to read an
attribute. So, what we're going to do is
I have this form here built out. And if
you look at it, um it is a form that
shows a picture of a dog. And when you
click the button, I want it to change to
a picture of a bear. If it's a bear, I
want to change back to being a dog. So,
what we're going to do here is the first
thing I need to do is I need to figure
out which picture is currently showing.
And I can figure that out by accessing
this source attribute. So I'm going to
say let current source equal
document.getelement
by ID and the ID is avatar.
And then I want to get its source
attribute. And so I'll say get attribute
and it says which attribute do you want
to get? I want to get the source.
Okay. So that'll read off the source.
And then um based on what that source
is, I want to change it. So um I'm going
to say let new image equal and then I'll
say if current source dot
includes
um and you'll notice the image for dog
has dog in it. So I'm going to say if it
includes dog
then I want to set it to the bear image
which I've defined right here.
If not, then I want to set it to the
doggo image. Okay, so I'm saying if the
current source, this right here,
includes dog, then I wanted to set it to
this bear image. If not, I want to set
it to this dog image. All right. And
then now we need to actually set it. So
all I've done is defined what the
variable is going to be. But now I'm
going to say document.getelement
by ID avatar.
and then set attribute. And what do I
want to set? Well, I want to set the
source. And what do I want to set its
value equal to? The new image.
So, if I save this and I come over, I've
got my dog image. Now, I've got a bear.
Now, I've got a dog. Now I've got a
bear.